Rohit Sharda

V Uttam Nagar, New Delhi, India
(+91) 9999780739
Date of birth 11-December-1988

rohitsharda88@gmail.comSkype rohitsharda88_1Nationality Indian

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior DevOps Engineer who believes in IaC (Infrastructure As Code) with experience in implementing DevOps principles, managing various Cloud Services and On-Premise DataCenter and Server Administration. Professional skills in CI/CD, Infrastructure Automation, Configuration Management, Container Orchestration and Programming Languages.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python 3, familiar with Java

Scripting Languages: Groovy, Bash Shell

AWS Cloud: Boto3, EKS, ACM, Auto Scaling, Aurora DB, Cloudfront, ELB/ALB, EC2, RDS,

Route 53, S3, VPC, IAM, SNS, SQS, Rekognition, Lambda

MS Azure Cloud: Application Gateway, Blob storage, Load Balancer, Virtual Machines, Virtual

Networks

laC Tools: CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible, Chef, Helm, Docker and Packer

Container Orchestrators : Kubernetes

CI/CD Tools: Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Jenkins

OS: Ubuntu, Centos, Windows Server, Kali, RHEL and Mac

Web and Application Servers: Apache Tomcat, IIS 6, Apache Httpd and Nginx

Build Tools: MSBuild, Gradle, Maven Database: MySQL and MongoDB Log Management Tools: ELK,Splunk

Other Tools: Vault, Consul, Pagerduty, Nexus, Prometheus

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior DevOps Engineer – Impressico Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Noida, (India) 30 November 2017 – Present

- Designed architecture of infrastructure and led their implementation.
- Built tools/scripts using Python, Java, Groovy and Javascript.
- Built projects based on IaC using Terraform, Ansible, Chef, Packer, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes and Helm.
- Implemented CI/CD using TeamCity and Jenkins Pipelines and Shared Libraries.
- Supported troubleshooting Dev/QA/Stage/Prod issues.
- Authored platform native scripts to manage Windows and Linux servers.
- Managed various cloud services on AWS, MS Azure, GCP, and Rackspace.

Sr System Administrator – HCL Infosystem., Noida, (India) 29 May 2016 – 29 November 2017

- Led DataCenter Migration to AWS. Setup Monitoring of application performance.
- Designed and implemented application architecture for HA environments.
- Acted as Product manager to design the product. Performed market research to determine what potential customers need in the product and designed the application based on the findings.
- Assessed market competition by comparing the company products to competitors products.

Server Engineer - Multisoft Systems Pvt. Ltd., Noida, (India) 01 Aug 2014 - 22 Feb 2016

- Automated Provisioning, Maintenance of Linux Servers and Deployment using Ansible.
- Managed AWS cloud services, implemented CI/CD using github and Jenkins.
- Containerised Applications using Docker and implemented Central log aggregation using EFK.
- Performed Server Hardening as per PCI DSS compliance
- Led Server Audits and Supported Incident Investigations.
- Performed Clustering of Apache Tomcat servers. Setup Monitoring of Servers
- Authored BASH shell scripts to generate reports, Create backups of server configurations and Mysql databases.
- Performed DataCenter Migration and built DR site.

IT Helpdesk - Intaglio Solution., New Delhi , (India) 1 April 2011 - 31 March 2014

• Performed User accounting, Monitoring and Maintenance of Linux servers

CERTIFICATIONS

• RED HAT CERTIFICATE OF EXPERTISE IN ANSIBLE AUTOMATION. (CERTIFICATE NUMBER: 170-189-153).

EDUCATION

January 2006 - 2011 : IGNOU

• B.C.A (Bacholer of Computer Application) & MCA (Master in Computer Applications)

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

• English : Fluent

• Hindi : Native speaker